Marco Zanini

Via Scipio Sighele, 32 Arco (TN), 38062, Italy (0039) 320 823 7345

chetto87@gmail.com

www.marcozanini.it

Innovative and involved software engineer with over three years of experience. Recognized high potential via bi-annual reviews. Fast and avid learner. Brought alternative and novel solutions to slowing projects. Perfectionist, takes pleasure in creating simple and beautiful information products, master in the art of code simplification. Excels in diverse and multicultural environments. Actively seeking new challenges.

Experience

Software Engineer, Schlumberger Paris region, France

Integral part of a five person team developing communication software for operating Schlumberger's pressure and sampling tools. Implements UI-based workflow for testing and maintaining Schlumberger's logging tools.

February, 2013 – June, 2016

C++/Boost, TDD, C#, WPF, TFS, Visual Studio

- Converted Matlab processing library to C++, removing the need for purchasing C++, Matlab, Armadillo Matlab licenses and halving execution time.
- Scrum Master of a five person team. Led a 15 person team in adopting new technical practices resulting in improved code quality and efficiency. Increased unit test coverage by 50% on single components.

Agile methodologies, Scrum, Extreme programming, TDD

Delivered first version of mobile monitoring system for well testing equipment, Requirement analysis, Financial developing all phases of the project life cycle. Constructed back-end and front- impact analysis, Android, Java, C#, end software: Web Service and an Android application. Predicted savings up to WCF, Android Studio, Gradle, Git \$5,000/job via workload reduction and safety improvement.

Researcher, The Irish Software Engineering Research Center (LERO) Limerick, Ireland

Developed adaptive system to enhance security in cloud computing environments, using federated identity management and SaaS cloud computing Apps for Business, Shibboleth services like Google Apps for Business. Project presented at IBM, Dublin.

Java, Cloud Computing, Google

October, 2011 - March, 2012

Education

Master of Science, Computer Engineering Polytechnic University of Milan

"Dingo": developed software capable of installing and running programs on clusters of machines, keeping them synchronized via file transferring through SSH. Shared on GitHub: https://github.com/mzanini/dingo

March 2010 - December 2012

Java, SSH, Jsch

Grade: 91/110 VHDL, C

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering Polytechnic University of Milan

Thesis: "Analysis and benchmarking of high level synthesis applications"

September 2006 – March 2010

"DOSE Project": team development of an online multi-player game in collaboration with students from Ukraine and Switzerland. The project was launched by ETH Zurich.

Eiffel programming

language

Interests

Self Improvement Getting Things Done,

The Pomodoro Technique, Mindfulness meditation

Peak half marathon: 1h 40min Running, Swimming, Rock Climbing **Web Development** Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS

https://github.com/mzanini/sample app https://github.com/mzanini/mzanini.github.io

Other information

Nationality: Italian **Italian**: Native **English**: Full professional **French**: Full professional